<tool id="select_subsets" name="Select subsets" version="1.0.0" force_history_refresh="True">
	<description>
		Create dataset(s) of selections user has made from a tabular dataset.
		A separate dataset is created for each group of selected items indicated
		by third column [a group key].  Fourth column is unique incremented id for each row.

		This tool can be used in combination with the Blast Reporting tool available
		in the https://toolshed.g2.bx.psu.edu/ toolshed.

		Produced by https://github.com/Public-Health-Bioinformatics
	</description>
	<command interpreter="python">
        select_subsets.py $input $output1 $output1.id $__new_file_path__ $incl_excl $select
	</command>
	<inputs>
		<param name="input" type="data" format="tabular" label="Numbered tabular input file"/>
		<param name="incl_excl" type="select" format="text" label="Include or exclude selection?">
			<option value="1">Include selection</option>
			<option value="0">Exclude selection</option>
		</param>
		<param name="select" type="select" multiple="true" display="checkboxes" label="Select lines below">
			<options from_dataset="input">
				<column name="name" index="0"/>
				<column name="value" index="-1"/>
			</options>
		</param>
	</inputs>
	<outputs>
		<data name="output1" format="tabular" metadata_source="input" label="$tool.name on data $input.hid"/>
	</outputs>
	<tests>
		<test>
			<param name="input" value="test_select_subsets.tabular"/>
                	<output name="output1" file="test_select_subsets_output.tabular"/>
			<param name="select" values="2,4,5,17"/>			
                	<param name="incl_excl" value="1"/>                                                
		</test>	
	</tests>
	<help>

.. class:: infomark

**What it does**

User selects groups of lines from a "Sequence Selection List" of tabular data rows.  
Each group will be created in a separate history dataset.

This tool can be used in conjunction with the BLAST Reporting tool's "Selectable HTML Report".  
When that report is selected, the tool also produces a "Sequence Selection List" of queries and hits,
which contains the necessary grouping and row index fields described below.  The HTML Report can directly
submit selections to the Select Subsets tool for processing.  That functionality requires Galaxy administrator setup.

----

.. class:: warningmark

Before using this tool, ensure the source tabular dataset has:

	1) Incremented row number in last column.  You can use the tool 
	**Add column to an existing dataset (Text Manipulation)** 
	with the parameters **Add this value: 1** and **Iterate?: YES**.  
	2) 2nd last column controls grouping:  If you want the tool to divide up your data 
	into separate datasets of selections, include a short Grouping key (&lt;10 chars) in this column.  
	If no grouping desired, leave this column empty. 

----

.. class:: warningmark

Galaxy reads only the first 1 MB of the input tabular file to generate the checkbox options. If your file is larger than 1 MB, consider
breaking it into smaller pieces before running this tool.

	</help>
</tool>
